India
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- India, 2.1.3.1.1.7
  - India, 1921-1922; 66 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal, with minarets, through doorway, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 67 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal, four minarets, man on left [3 copies], 1
    - Verso: The finest tribute that was ever paid by man to the memory of woman, the sight that men journey all the way across the world to see, the most beautiful building on earth, the Taj Mahal, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 68 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal through doorway, four minarets, man in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 69 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal from balcony of gate, clouds, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 70 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal from balcony of gate, slightly side view, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 71 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal, distance. Fine clouds., 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 72 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal from balcony, quite a few people., 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 73 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal from balcony, fine clouds, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 74 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal from balcony, fine clouds, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 75 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal, lilies and man, reflection in pool [2 copies], 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 76 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal, trees in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 77 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 78 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal, side view, three minarets, clouds, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 79 (Box 1503)
    - Portrait of Mumtaz Mahal, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 80 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal in distance, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 81 (Box 1503)
    - Inside Agra Fort, Taj Mahal in distance, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 82 (Box 1503)
    - Taj Mahal in distance, columns and man in foreground, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 83 (Box 1503)
    - Jasmine tower through pillars, jasmine tower in distance., 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 84 (Box 1503)
    - Human Parcheesi game, 1
    - Note: Akbar the Great, the leading Moghul ruler of India, many centuries ago, used this terrace to play a game of parchesi, using beautiful slave girls as the playing pieces. The Emperor and some noble of his court would sit on the raised dais, where L.T. is sitting. The Emperor and his companion would play the game in a way that would result in either one or the other winning most of the beautiful girls, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 85 (Box 1503)
    - Pulpit, mosque Sikri., 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 86 (Box 1503)
    - Carved pillar, Sheikh Shisti smelling flowers, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 87 (Box 1503)
    - Building where Akbar held religious discussions, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 88 (Box 1503)
    - Old Sadhu with turban made of three rows of beads [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: An ash-smeared mendicant who watched the arrival of the World Fliers at Allahabad on the banks of the sacred Ganges, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 89 (Box 1503)
    - Two Sadhus close-up, pyramid shaped caste marks on foreheads, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 90 (Box 1503)
    - Sadhu wearing glasses, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 91 (Box 1503)
    - Sadhu with cocoanut shell hat, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 92 (Box 1503)
    - Educated Sadhu near Tinnevelly, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 93 (Box 1503)
    - Sadhu with very small loin cloth, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 94 (Box 1503)
    - Sadhu looking to the side, 1
  Box 1504
- India, 2.1.3.1.1.7
  - India, 1921-1922; 1 (Box 1504)
    - Group of Sadhus, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 2 (Box 1504)
    - Hanuman the monkey god and a Sadhu, 1
    - Verso: The Hindu Monkey God Hanuman., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 3 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu seated on a mat, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 4 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu who raised dead, squatting, close-up, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 5 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu who raised dead surrounded by disciples, 1
    - Note: L.T. attending an afternoon session at which a famous Hindu Holy Man is instructing his followers in some of the secrets of oriental mysticism. The Holy Man, with the beard, claims to have the power of bringing animals back to life after they are dead, and his followers claim that he does all kind of other miracles., 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 6 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu covered with earth, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 7 (Box 1504)
    - Two Sadhus sitting on bed of spikes, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 8 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu sitting on spikes, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 9 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu squatting under palm leaf shelter, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 10 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu with white around eyes and rakish turban, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 11 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu with mouth open, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 12 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu with elephantiasis, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 13 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu with big rock on stomach, close-up, 1
    - Verso: Sadhu with rock on stomach, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 14 (Box 1504)
    - Deformed man on little cart, front view, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 15 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu with deformed hands and feet, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 16 (Box 1504)
    - Two Sadhus covered with garlands of flowers and papers, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 17 (Box 1504)
    - Sadhu carrying sticks under arm and dish on head, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 18 (Box 1504)
    - Four men with sacred white bull, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 19 (Box 1504)
    - Rolling Sadhu with baby, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 20 (Box 1504)
    - Ugly Sadhu, close-up of face, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 21 (Box 1504)
    - Hindu girl with nose bangles and hands on breast, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 22 (Box 1504)
    - Woman with swollen foot and toes, close-up of foot, 1
    - Verso: Woman with elephantitus. India, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 23 (Box 1504)
    - Woman Sadhu with fingers together, 1
    - Note: L.T. supervising filming of a scene, in India, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 24 (Box 1504)
    - Unidentified jurist wearing white wig, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 25 (Box 1504)
    - Woman with deformed legs, 1
    - Verso: Hindu woman with deformed legs. India, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 26 (Box 1504)
    - Road through barren Waziristan, 1
    - Verso: A British outpost on the Afghan frontier, the world's navel of bedevilment, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 27 (Box 1504)
    - Aviator's ransom letter [4 copies], 1
    - Verso: Every British aviator wears this ransom letter sewn in his flying jacket. It tells the tribesmen they will receive a reward of $3000 if they bring the airman in safely, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 28 (Box 1504)
    - Young man with moustache wearing turban, smiling, 1
    - Verso: An Afghan lade, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 29 (Box 1504)
    - Brigands waiting behind rock, 1
    - Verso: Afghan bandits waiting to waylay a caravan., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 30 (Box 1504)
    - Afridi house, Francis Yeats-Brown and crowd, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 31 (Box 1504)
    - Two dead men and automobile, close-up, showing wheels, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 32 (Box 1504)
    - Two dead men and automobile, 1
    - Verso: Pictures of a raid on the Indian frontier. The wild tribesmen who inhabit the hills between India and Afghanistan are the most bloodthirsty brigands on earth, 1-verso
    - Two dead men and automobile, 2
    - Verso: A mail car waylaid by brigands on the Indo-Afghan frontier, 2-verso
    - Two dead men and automobile, 3
  - India, 1921-1922; 33 (Box 1504)
    - Tribesman shooting over wall, 1
    - Verso: An Afghan feudist taking a pot shot at a neighbor, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 34 (Box 1504)
    - Trafalgar Square, Lundi Kotal, Lowell Thomas with foot on running board of automobile, 1
    - Verso: Lidi Kotal - Trafalgar Square, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 35 (Box 1504)
    - Buick automobile crossing border, 1
    - Note: L.T. and party passing through the barbed wire barricade that marks the boundary between India and Afghanistan, at the western end of the famous Khyber Pass, the most strongly fortified mountain gorge in the world. Any one crossing this border without the consent of the Afghan King is almost certain to have his throat cut, in the name of Allah, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 36 (Box 1504)
    - Buick automobile in sand, Lowell Thomas, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 37 (Box 1504)
    - Buick automobile in front of tower fort, 1
    - Note: L.T. and party at a roadside fort in the wild country of Afghanistan., 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 38 (Box 1504)
    - Soldier stopping automobile near frontier, Lowell Thomas at right, 1
    - Note: L.T. being held up by frontier patrols at the border between India and Afghanistan, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 39 (Box 1504)
    - Three veiled women on donkeys, 1
    - Verso: Pathan women on their way to Peshawar., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 40 (Box 1504)
    - Afghan fife and drum musicians, 1
    - Verso: The spirit of 1930 in the Land of the Hindu Kush a Pathan dance, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 41 (Box 1504)
    - Old man on donkey, dog and man walking, 1
    - Verso: An Afghan patriarch on his Rolls Royce, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 42 (Box 1504)
    - Cobbler with man squatting on each side of him, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 43 (Box 1504)
    - Scraggly patriarch, one hand on shoulder, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 44 (Box 1504)
    - One man wearing black turban, one wearing turban like flying helmet, 1
    - Verso: Mendicants along the "golden road" across Afghanistan which leads from Peshawar to Samarkand., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 45 (Box 1504)
    - Afghan sitting, smoking hookah, big white turban, 1
    - Verso: A typical Afghan of Kabul enjoying a smoke in the caravanserai at Peshawar, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 46 (Box 1504)
    - Jalalabad Gate, Lowell Thomas driving automobile, talking to old man with donkey, 1
    - Note: Contrast in transportation, at one of the gates of the Walled City of Jalalabad, in Afghanistan. L.T. at the wheel, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 47 (Box 1504)
    - Jalalabad Palace, side view, 1
    - Note: L.T. and party on the left, at the King's Palace, in Jalalabad, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 48 (Box 1504)
    - Panorama of Kabul, four men in foreground, 1
    - Note: L.T. and party on one of the barren hills just above the city of Kabul, capital of the little-known country of Afghanistan., 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 49 (Box 1504)
    - Crowd at Great Mosque, kneeling, 1
    - Note: A picture made by L.T. from the walls of the Great Mosque in Kabul, the Afghan capital, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 50 (Box 1504)
    - Harry Chase, Lowell Thomas and Amir in automobile, Kabul [3 copies], 1
    - Note: L.T. and party in the city of Kabul. They are wearing the Afghan headdress, the so-called Afghan tarbush, made of Persian lamb. They did this at the request of the Amir of Afghanistan so that they would look as much like young Turks as possible. Christians are not welcome in the land of the Afghans, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 51 (Box 1504)
    - Niam Shah and Harry Chase, 1
    - Verso: Niam Shah + Chase. India, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 52 (Box 1504)
    - Niam Shah and Lowell Thomas, 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas at the court of the Amir of Afghanistan in a forbidden part of central Asia., 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 53 (Box 1504)
    - Mohammed Dali Khan (Afghan minister for foreign affairs) and four high representatives in full dress, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 54 (Box 1504)
    - Bolshevik minister and wife, 1
    - Verso: The Bolshevik envoy and wife in Kabul, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 55 (Box 1504)
    - Fakhri Pasha, full dress, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 56 (Box 1504)
    - Mohammed Dali Khan (Afghan minister for foreign affairs) in full dress, 1
    - Verso: Mohammed Wali Khan, one of Amanullah's chief nobles who assisted him in his fight to regain his throne
    - Mohammed Dali Khan (Afghan minister for foreign affairs) in full dress, 2
    - Verso: Afghanistan-No.59; Vali Muhammad Khan, Afghan Minister for Foreign Affairs. Although the Amir has never been out of his country, this member of his cabinet has recently returned from a world tour. Among other countries he visited the United States hoping to be able to get the President to send a permanent diplomatic official to the Amir's capital. Although Afghanistan has long been a forbidden land the new ruler is so anxious that his country shall play a prominent part in world affairs that he is inviting foreign powers to send ministers. It is rumoured the Afghan minister for Foreign Affairs considered he was shabbily treated in Washington because he was not officially recognized, although finally did meet President Harding and Secretary of State Hughes, informally. But America has not decided to send a diplomatic officer to the Amir's court. Nevertheless the American Charge d'Affairs at the Court of the Shah of Persia was asked to find out all he could about Afghanistan and make a report. It was through him that Mr. Lowell Thomas was at last successful in his wish to penetrate into the land of the Afghans. -He is acting as King in the Amir's absence at present!
  - India, 1921-1922; 57 (Box 1504)
    - Amir in ordinary riding suit, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 58 (Box 1504)
    - Amir, father-in-law, baby, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 59 (Box 1504)
    - Amir and three companions in tennis costumes sitting on bench [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Left to right, The Amir, Field Marshal Shah Wali Khan, and two Afghan cabinet ministers. The men around the Amir are keen sportsmen like himself, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 60 (Box 1504)
    - Two lamp posts, rookery, high mountains, 1
    - Note: L.T. Standing in the foreground with a cane under his arm, looking up at one of the mountains of Afghanistan, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 61 (Box 1504)
    - Abdul Rachman's palace at sunset, from vineyard, 1
    - Verso: One of the Amir's palaces in Kabul now in the hands of wild Shinwari tribesmen, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 62 (Box 1504)
    - Friend of Amir standing under wooden arch, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 63 (Box 1504)
    - Amir's youngest brother, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 64 (Box 1504)
    - Amir's second brother, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 65 (Box 1504)
    - Lowell Thomas talking to Amir and brothers with back turned, 1
    - Note: L.T. with back to the camera, being welcomed by the Amir of the Afghans, in the city of Kabu. The Amir is in the center of the group, wearing the riding boots. The heavyset gentleman in the white turban and robe, is his brother, who succeeded him as King, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 66 (Box 1504)
    - Amir and commander of army, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 67 (Box 1504)
    - Amir after tennis match, standing [man at left cropped out], 1
    - Verso: Amanullah as a tennis player. His subjects objected to all of his western ideas, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 68 (Box 1504)
    - Amir's two daughters with little deer, 1
    - Verso: Amanullah Khan and daughters, and pet deer, 1-verso
    - Amir's two daughters with little deer, 2
    - Verso: The Amir and his two daughter[s] with their pet deer, 2-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 69 (Box 1504)
    - Amir on horse coming out of palace gate, 1
    - Verso: The Amir rides forth to the mosque; 9-1001, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 70 (Box 1504)
    - Cavalry colonel on horse, 1
    - Verso: An Afghan colonel of cavalry, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 71 (Box 1504)
    - Two generals on horses, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 72 (Box 1504)
    - General on horse and Lowell Thomas, 1
    - Note: L.T. and Shaw Wali Khan, Commander-in-Chief of the Afghan army, at a special review of military forces of Afghanistan, held outside the city of Kabul, in honor of L.T., 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 73 (Box 1504)
    - General standing by horse's head, Afghanistan, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 74 (Box 1504)
    - Infantry pointing rifles, 1
    - Verso: Afghan infantrymen. These are Kafirs, descendents of the army of Alexander the Great. They are neighbors of the Afridi's and live in the mountains northwest of Peshawar, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 75 (Box 1504)
    - Elephant making concrete, distant, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 76 (Box 1504)
    - Elephant making concrete, 1
    - Elephant making concrete. India, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 77 (Box 1504)
    - Lowell Thomas in motor truck, 1
    - Note: L.T. journeying in a most unromantic motortruck on his way to the most romantic place in the world, the beautiful Vale of Kashmir, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 78 (Box 1504)
    - Jhelum River and gorge, 1
    - Note: A picture of the Jelum River, on the way to the Vale of Kashmir, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 79 (Box 1504)
    - One bullock cart, three bullocks, distant, 1
    - Verso: Bullock cart, 3 bullocks distant, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 80 (Box 1504)
    - Kashmir Valley, cypress avenue in distance, 1
    - Verso: Kashmir valley - cypress avenue in distance, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 81 (Box 1504)
    - Srinagar Canal, fort and mountains in distance, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 82 (Box 1504)
    - Dal Lake lotus blossoms, mountains in background, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 83 (Box 1504)
    - Fisherman spearing, Dal Lake, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 84 (Box 1504)
    - Four fishermen spearing, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 85 (Box 1504)
    - Shalimar garden, man pointing, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 86 (Box 1504)
    - Residency gardens, four men and Lowell Thomas, 1
    - Note: L.T. and party in the Garden of Shalimar in the Vale of Kashmir, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 87 (Box 1504)
    - Sweeper with basket, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 88 (Box 1504)
    - Milk boy[?] and servant [servant cut out of photograph], 1
  Box 1505
- India, 2.1.3.1.1.7
  - India, 1921-1922; 1 (Box 1505)
    - Lowell Thomas being carried along a road in a dandy chair [3 copies], 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas returning to the plains of India from the hills station of Musurriee in a palanquin, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 2 (Box 1505)
    - Lord Rawlinson and polo team, distant [2 copies], 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 3 (Box 1505)
    - Note: L.T. with a Sikh officer of the Indian army, 1
    - Note: L.T. in conversation with a resplendent native officer of the Indian army, 2
    - Note: L.T. chatting with a cobbler in one of the cities in India, 3
    - Lowell Thomas and Indian officer, 4
    - Verso: L.T. with a Sikh officer of the Indian army, 4-verso
    - Lowell Thomas and Indian officer, 5
    - Verso: A Graphlex Chase tools months ago. Talking ti an old Indian Army officer, 5-verso
    - Lowell Thomas and Indian officer, 6
    - Lowell Thomas and Indian officer, 7
    - Lowell Thomas and Indian officer, 8
  - India, 1921-1922; 4 (Box 1505)
    - Lowell Thomas in dress suit standing, talking to station master, 1
    - Note: L.T. palavering with the driver of a Lahore ekka, 2
  - India, 1921-1922; 5 (Box 1505)
    - Sheik Mahid and man sitting at base of Victorian monument, close-up, corner of monument, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 6 (Box 1505)
    - Sanchi stupa seen through arch, man in arch, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 7 (Box 1505)
    - Tower of Silence, close-up, with many vultures, 1
    - Verso: Tower of silence with vultures. India, 1-verso
  - India, 1921-1922; 8 (Box 1505)
    - Statue of Lord Clive in London, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 9 (Box 1505)
    - Boatman with red beard, 1
  - India, 1921-1922; 10 (Box 1505)
    - Prince of Wales in full uniform, 1
    - Verso: H.R.H. Prince of Wales, 1-verso